Michael Walsh

47 The Leyes, Osbaldwick, York YO10 3PR

Telephone: 07429593907 Email: miw503@york.ac.uk
Github: github.com/Mikeywalsh
Website: michaelwalsh.co.uk

Personal Profile

I am a third year Computer Science student at the University of York. Driven by a lifelong interest in computing, I consider myself to be a highly motivated, hard working individual. I have years of experience programming, have a large portfolio of personal projects, and have real world experience working as a software engineer. I eagerly await the opportunity to build on my technological skills.

Education & Qualifications

2015 - Present Computer Science BEng, University of York

- Expected final grade 1st
- First year 67%, Second year 68%
- Modules include: Vision and Graphics, Artificial Intelligence, Neural Computing and Applications,
 Theory and Practice of Programming and a Software Engineering Project
- Final year project Developing visualisations of Monte Carlo Tree Search
- Achieved the York award during my first year

2012 - 2015 Winstanley College, Wigan

- A-levels Maths (A), Computing (B), Physics (C)
- AS-Levels Further Maths (C)

2007 - 2012 All Saints Catholic Centre For Learning, Liverpool

- o GCSEs: 10 A* C, Including Maths and English
- BTECs: IT (Distinction*), Business (Pass)

Work Experience

Jun 2017 – Sep 2017 Software Engineering Internship, MBDA, Bristol

- o A multi-national world leading aerospace and defence engineering company
- I worked on a project called FLAADS Land, using C++, in a tight-knit group of other software engineers
- Heavily used tools such as Google Test, GCovr, Rational Team Concert(source control)
- I had contact with other departments and visited other sites, giving me an insight into the part software played in the overall project and the importance of communication between teams
- Over the course of the internship, I was exposed to software engineering at an industrial level and experienced a sizeable chunk of the development lifecycle of a real world project

Nov 2015 – May 2017 Catering Assistant, National Railway Museum, York

- o Part of the British Science Museum Group focusing on the history of rail transport, based in York
- I worked in the various cafe's located inside of the museum, both during the day and as part of booked events in the evening/night
- I worked as part of a team to serve and wait on customers, set up for events and maintain the appearance of the museum

Jun 2016 – Jul 2016 Contracted Software Development, Zamzar Ltd.

- An England based company specialising in online file conversion
- After winning a prize in a hackathon hosted by Zamzar, they contracted me to finish my software
- My software made use of both Zamzar's and Dropbox's API to create a hot-drop type folder in Dropbox that would automatically convert any input file into a specified output format
- Had constant contact with Zamzar throughout
- o By the time I had finished, I had learned a lot about software development in the real world

Extra Curricular

Projects

- MCTS Visualisation My final year university project focusing on different ways to graphically represent Monte Carlo Tree Search in 3D, using C# with Unity3d
- o Chipster A very fast Chip-8 emulator written in C#, making use of OpenTK for graphics
- RpsNet An online Rock-Paper-Scissors game made in Java using Kryonet and LibGDX, featuring a fully functional matchmaking system which uses a central game server and multiple clients
- Buttons and Boxes A 3D puzzle game built in Unity3d with C# and PHP, featuring a level editor and server that allows players to share levels amongst themselves. I got to showcase this game at the opening of the York Digital Creativity Labs in 2016, as part of the Game Development Society at university
- Tank Wars A top down shooter built in Unity2d with C#
- I have also collaborated on several open source projects, including LibGDX, a Java games framework

Hackathons

- Zamzar hackathon 1st Place University of York, June 2016
- Bank of America hackathon 2nd Place University of York, November 2016
- York Instruments hackathon 1st Place University of York, June 2017
- o I have also taken part in the Global Game Jam, Google Hashcode, Ludum Dare and Durhack

Skills

- o Programming Languages C#, Java, C++, Python, PHP, Visual Basic
- Frameworks .Net, LibGDX, OpenGL, NUnit, JUnit, Google Test
- o Tools Visual Studio, IntelliJ, Unity Engine, Windows, Linux

References

Available on request